Guide to the American Printing History Association records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: President's Files, 1972-2000
  - Subseries II.6: Irene Tichenor Files, 1984-2001
    - Re. APHA Newsletter file, 2000-2001 (Box 35)
    - File relating to Vice President for Publications, 1984-1990 (Box 35)
    - APHA Awards, 2000 (Box 35)
    - Conference, 2000 (Box 35)
    - Conference, 2001 (Box 35)
    - APHA Logo Competition, 2000-2001 (Box 35)
    - Elizabeth K Lieberman's death, 2001 (Box 35)
    - Photographs (45), ca. 2000 (Box 35)
- Series III: Chapters, 1975-2001
  This series contains material related to the establishment and activities of local chapters. The records include announcements, bylaws, correspondence, financial records, lists of members and officers, meeting materials, minutes, newsletters, and press releases.
  - Subseries III.1: General Files, 1975-1987
    Contains a few general files on APHA chapters.
    - Chapters, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - APHA Approved Chapters, 1982-1987 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - APHA Chapters, 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Subseries III.2: New York Chapter Files, 1976-1996
    Includes announcements, bylaws, correspondence, financial records, lists of members and officers, meeting materials and minutes, and press releases.
    - General
      - New York Chapter, 1982-1984 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - New York Chapter, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 9)
        (Membership list)
      - APHA/NY Current, 1984-1996 (Box 12, Folder 8)
        (From Kenneth Milford)
    - Alphabetical
      - Board Meetings--Minutes, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Bylaws, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Meetings
        - Meeting Announcements, 1976-1979 (Box 6, Folder 11)
        - Meetings and Other Materials, 1981-1986 (Box 1, Folder 16 to 17)
      - Membership and Mailing Lists, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Miscellaneous, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
        (Mainly relates to the nominating committee and financial issues)
      - Officers and Board Members, 1974-1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Press Releases, 1976, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Program Meetings
        - Announcements, 1976-1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
        - Correspondence, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Lowell Bodger Files
      - New York Chapter By-Laws, 1974, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Officers, 1980-1985 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Dinners, 1985-1987 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Membership Lists, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - Membership Card File, 1976-1985
      - Financial Statements, 1975-1985 (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - Secretary Minutes, 1979-1985 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - APHA National, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Contributions, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Meeting Notices, 1982-1985 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Treasurer's Ledger, 1976-1980 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Subseries III.3: Other Chapter Files, 1975-2001
    includes small quantities of records related to local chapters in Alabama, California, New England, Philadelphia, and the Southeast. The records for Alabama, California, and New England contain newsletters and information on the establishment of the chapters. Although most of the records for Philadelphia chapter are from the 1990s, there are records from its whole life span of 1983-1998, when it merged with the Chesapeake chapter. These records include bylaws, correspondence, and lists of members and officers.
    - Alabama, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - California
      - Northern California (San Francisco), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Southern California, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - New England
      - 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        (Newsletters)
      - Newsletters and Announcements, 1980-1988 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Boston, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 15)
        (On formation of a Boston area chapter)
      - Philadelphia
        - General
          - 1983-1998 (Box 12, Folder 3)
          - 1994-1997 (Box 31, Folder 7)
        - Phila/Pennsylvania Prospects, 1987-1988 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Southeastern Chapter, 1996-2001 (Box 31, Folder 8)
- Series IV: Publications, 1975-2002
  This series contains records related to the publication of APHA's journal, newsletter, and other publications. The majority of the records consist of correspondence files related to submissions to the newsletter or the journal, but there is also some material related to book reviews, copyright, finances, printing, and proposed projects.
  APHA's main publications, the APHA Newsletter and Printing History, are separately cataloged and filed with the Graphic Arts book collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library.
  - Subseries IV.1: Catherine Brody, 1975-1985
    Brody served as the editor for the APHA newsletter. Her files include correspondence on new items submitted for inclusion in the newsletter.
    - APHA, 1978-1984 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence on the APHA newsletter, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - APHA, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - APHA, 1975-1982 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - APHA Correspondence, 1981 December (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - APHA, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - APHA, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Untitled, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - APHA, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Book Reviews, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - APHA, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Subseries IV.2: Printing History, 1978-1998
    Consists mainly of correspondence files related to submissions. These records were kept by Anna Lou Ashby and other editors of Printing History. The files also include information on copyright, finances, ideas, printing arrangements, and the origins of Printing History.
    - Anna Lou Ashby Files
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Articles Not Accepted, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous for Finding Reviews, 1981-1982, Undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - #10 (December 1983), 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - #11, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - #12, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - #2, 1978-1980 (Box 10, Folder 13)
        (Book reviews)
      - Books to Consider for Review, 1978-1980 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - #3, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - APHA Reviews First Issues, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - #5, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Copyright, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence
      - Articles, Correspondence on
        - Article Solicitations, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
        - Eckman, James--Chicago type foundry #17, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - #17 Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        - Profile Kono, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
          (Takashi Kono)
        - Stoddard, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
          (#17)
        - Alterman--Tibetan Orthography, 1985, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 9 to 10)
        - Elizabeth Harris--Printing for the Blind #16, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 12)
        - Donald Krummel--Music Printing #16, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 13)
        - Lily Chia-jen Kecskes--Chinese Ink and Inkmaking #15, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 15)
        - Roderick Cave, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 16)
          (#20)
        - Book Reviews #15, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 17)
        - Virginia Smith--Longevity and Legibility #15, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 18)
        - Sybille Fraser--Underground Printing #15, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 19)
        - Susan M. Allen, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 20)
        - #13, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 21)
        - Environment, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 4)
        - Review Copies #17-18, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - #17, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 6)
        - John Lent--The Stockdale Women of Bermuda, 1986-1988 (Box 9, Folder 7)
        - Untitled, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 8)
          (Correspondence on the use of Kellogg's logo for an article)
        - August Brunsman--Wright and Wright, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 9)
        - Gay Walker--Meriden Gravure and the U.S. Government, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 10)
        - Reviewer on Peterson's Article for #17, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 13)
        - Dr. Leslie's Obituary--#18, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 14)
        - David Woodward--Map Printing--#16, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 15)
        - Pamela Petro, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 16)
        - Stephen Saxe, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 17)
          (Comment on Fredric Brewer)
        - Hope Mayo, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 18)
        - Tanselle #18, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 19)
        - Harmsen #18, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 20)
        - Victor Margolin--Paul Theobald & Company, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 21)
        - Sue Allen, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - Other Correspondence
        - General, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 23)
        - Number One-Number Four, 1978-1980, (4 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 24 to 27)
        - Press (Leonid), 1986 (Box 4, Folder 11)
          (on the printing of #16)
        - Pizzo, Tony #15, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 14)
          (Meriden-Stinehour Press on printing issues for the journal)
        - Correspondence with the Printer, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Finances, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      (Preliminary Budget)
    - Moretus Press, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      (Publishing agreement drafts)
    - Origins, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      (Report of journal committee; program for the journal's launch reception)
    - Number 4, 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Number 6-Number 9, 1981-1983 June (3 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 2 to 4)
    - Number 11, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Books Not Reviews, circa 1982-1984 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Number 12-Number 16, 1984-1986 (Box 26, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Current, 1983-1986 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Ideas, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Subseries IV.3: Other Publications and Projects, 1975-2002
    Consists of material related to publication projects unrelated to the APHA newsletter or Printing History. The subseries includes a copy of the Directory of Founding Members, as well as records related to its copyright. There are also records related to the publication of American Proprietary Types, Spiral Press Bibliography and D.B.U. and R.R.: selected extracts from correspondence between Daniel Berkeley Updike and Rudolph Ruzicka, 1908-1941. There is also a grant application and a proposal related to a unpublished project entitled, Publishing and Printing History: A Guide to Manuscript Resources in the United States.
    - Directory of Founding Members
      - Directory of Founding Members, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Copyright, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Publishing and Printing History: A Guide to Manuscript Resources in the United States
      - Proposal, circa 1980 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - APHA/NEH, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Ruzicka/Updike, 1996-1999 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      (This is D.B.U. and R.R.: selected extracts from correspondence between Daniel Berkeley Updike and Rudolph Ruzicka, 1908-1941.)
    - Spiral Press Bibliography, 2002 (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Series V: General Files, 1974-1998
  This series contains material that was specifically saved or filed for the APHA archives, but left in unsorted general files. Many of these files appear to have been kept by the secretaries of the board, and the records in these files are roughly chronological in arrangement. The series contains a wide variety of records including announcements, brochures, correspondence, lists of officers, memoranda, minutes, programs, and material related to annual meetings, the board of directors, chapters, committees, conferences, elections, and meetings.
  - Terry Belanger Files
    - Miscellaneous, 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 2 to 3)
    - 1991-1992 "To Be Sorted," 1990-1992, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 4 to 5)
    - APHA Archives, 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - APHA Archives, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Unfiled Material, 1974-1983 (Box 6, Folder 3 to 6)
    - Material for APHA Archives, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Untitled, 1980-1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Untitled, 1974-1976, (4 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 1 to 4)
    (Includes board and committee minutes, members' lists, mailing samples, etc. Appears to be the file of Joe Dunlap, Secretary of the Board)
  - APHA/Untitled, 1974-1995, (7 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 9 to 15)
    (Includes material on annual meetings, board meetings, and elections)
  - APHA, 1974-1992 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - APHA from Lili Wronker, 1995-1998, Undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    (Includes brochures for 20th APHA conference; publication of selected correspondence between David Updike and Rudolf Ruzicka)
  - Cathy Brody Files
    - APHA, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - APHA, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - APHA, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - APHA, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 12)